Satyakant Kantarao

Graduate student at Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

satyaintj@gmail.com

Summary

Control Systems engineer with a background in signal processing, mathematics, and project-specific domain knowledge in Electrical, Chemical & Mechanical Engg., and 4 years' work experience in academia.

Currently in a PhD program doing research on control algorithms for vehicle stability

Doctoral research uses MATLAB/Simulink, CarSim, and a H-i-L setup using PXI, XEP100 board and LabVIEW RT.

Post-PhD, seeking challenging research opportunities to apply control science & C, C++ programming to any problem and in any domain of practical relevance, with a preference for automotive systems.

Experience

Graduate student at Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

July 2007 - Present (6 years 2 months)

Lecturer; Asst. Professor at College of Engineering, Pune

July 2003 - July 2007 (4 years 1 month)

Teaching undergraduate and graduate courses in the Dept. of Electrical Engineering

Subjects taught — Automatic Control Systems, Digital Signal Processing, Digital Control, Introductory C++, Numerical Methods using MATLAB, Linear Algebra, Quantitative Feedback Theory, Introduction to MATLAB and Simulink

Additional responsibility: Computer Lab In-charge

Software and hardware maintenance of 20-40 computers, several of them being dual-bootable on Windows and Linux OS

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

PhD, Systems & Control Engineering, 2007 - 2014

Grade: 8.52/10.0

Activities and Societies: Debating; Hostel council (various responsibilities)

The Johns Hopkins University

MSE, Electrical Engineering, 1998 - 2000

Grade: 3.0/4.0

Activities and Societies: Jhankaar (Indian cultural club at JHU)

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

MTech, Systems & Control Engineering, 1996 - 1998

Grade: 8.47/10.0

Activities and Societies: Hostel magazine (joint chief editor; additional responsibility for operations &

logistics)

College of Engineering Pune

BE, Electrical Engineering, 1992 - 1996

Publications

Application and Evaluation of a Linear/Restricted Nonlinear Observer to a Nonlinear CSTR

May 30, 2001

Authors: Satyakant Kantarao

• S. Dash, S. Kantharao, R. Rengaswamy and V. Venkatasubramanian,

"Application and Evaluation of a Linear/Restricted Nonlinear Observer to a Nonlinear CSTR",

11th European Symposium on Computer Aided Process Engineering (ESCAPE), Kolding, Denmark, May 27-30, 2001

Languages

English(Native or bilingual proficiency)Hindi(Native or bilingual proficiency)Marathi(Native or bilingual proficiency)Telugu(Professional working proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Labview
Matlab
Simulink
Algorithms
Signal Processing
Control Systems Design
C++
Programming

 \mathbf{C}

Satyakant Kantarao

Graduate student at Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

satyaintj@gmail.com



Contact Satyakant on LinkedIn